Ronald T. Bare

207 Logue Rd * Mount Juliet, TN 37122 * 615-881-0624 * travisbare@gmail.com

Profile

Full-Stack development at Vanderbilt Coding Bootcamp. M. Ed. in Instructional Effectiveness, B.S. in Industrial Technology, searching for a full-time, software development position. I have a passion for programming and computer science. Twenty years of experience in teaching computer/technical courses. Proven leadership abilities and troubleshooting skills.

Experience

2010 – 2018 Instructor, Art Institute of Tennessee-Nashville, Nashville, TN

- writing lesson plans, administrative tasks
- Media Arts and Animation Department
- courses: History of Animation, Hard Surface and Organic Modeling, CG Lighting and Texturing, Advanced Lighting, 3D Modeling, Character and Technical Modeling, Perspective Drawing, 3D Character Animation, 3D Character Rigging, Digital Modeling, 3D Animation, Motion Graphics &VFX
- occasional In-service presentations

2010 – 2012 Teacher, Metro Nashville Public Schools (Cane Ridge High School), Nashville, TN

- implementing and maintaining classroom management procedures
- developing the CAD/Design program, writing lesson plans
- subjects include Computer-Aided Design, Advanced Drafting, and Design
- occasional In-service presentations

1997 – 2010 *Instructor*, ITT Technical Institute, Nashville, TN

- writing lesson plans, implementing and maintaining classroom management procedures
- focus areas are Multimedia and Computer Aided Drafting and Design
- class subjects: 3D Modeling and Animation, Rapid Visualization, Basic Design Theory and Methods, Digital Information Management, Physical and Computer 3D Modeling, Descriptive Geometry, Architecture I & II, Engineering Graphics I & II, Civil Drafting and GIS

1995-1997 Mechanical Designer, Line Power Manufacturing, Bristol, VA.

- created technical drawings for the industrial and design engineers using AutoCAD
- tolerances of metal, plastics and PCB components
- quoting functions included finding alternate components and specifications
- process routings and PCB machine routings

Computer Skills

HTML, CSS, Javascript/Jquery, Git and Github, Node.js, Linux, Visual Basic, MS Office, Various 2D and 3D graphics programs, upgrading/troubleshooting hardware.

Education/Certificates

Master of Education in Instructional Effectiveness

Trevecca Nazarene University GPA:4.0 2003

Certified Drafter

American Design and Drafting Assoc.

Bachelor of Science in Industrial Technology

Berea College 1992

Regional Accreditation

18 graduate hrs. Multimedia and Animation

Linux+ Certificate

Brainbench

Vanderbilt Coding Bootcamp

Full-Stack (6 mos.) 2019